《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
ADAMA: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我有一条信息要给你
I have a message for you.
两个人的(爱情)之果还活在世上
The fruit born of two peoples is alive.
一个以全知的宙斯的
A child named after
妻子和姐妹名字命名的孩子
the wife and sister of the all-knowing Zeus,
赫拉还活着
Hera, lives.
那不是真的
It's not true.
我不指望你告诉我这个中原由是什么
SAM: I don't suppose you're gonna tell me what this is all about.
我意思是  这孩子有多重要
I mean, what's so important about this kid?
她在将来可能十分重要
She may very well be the shape of things to come.
赛昂人确切知道我们所在的位置
The Cylons knew exactly where we were gonna be.
那并不能说明艾伦    我什么也没干
Well, that doesn't mean Ellen... I didn't do anything!
这是那张地图  上校!
This is the map, Colonel!
我画给你的那张  在你帐篷里给你的那张
The map that I drew for you. I gave this to you in your tent.
你本应该烧掉的  但你妻子说帮你去烧
You were gonna burn it, but then your wife offered to do it for you.
她没烧掉  对吧?
But she didn't, did she?
我...我可以解释
I... I want to explain...
他说他会杀了你的    谁说的?
He said he'd kill you... Who said it?
其中一个卡维尔
One of the Brother Cavils.
她是凯西
This is Kacey.
凯西  这是卡拉  你的母亲
Kacey, this is Kara, your mother.
我们的人就开始攻击机场 拘留中心
Our people are gonna attack the airbase, the detention center,
电站  还有其他关键设施
power station, and other critical facilities.
这个计划就是要在卡拉狄加与帕伽索斯到达时
The plan is to sow as much chaos and confusion as possible
尽可能制造混乱
the moment Galactica and Pegasus arrive.
不会有帕伽索斯  只有卡拉狄加
No Pegasus. Just Galactica.
这是给你的命令
These are your orders.
带上这些平民船只  等我18小时
Take the civilian fleet, and wait for me for 18 hours.
如果18小时后我没回来  那就去找地球吧
If I'm not back in 18 hours, then find Earth.
你们也知道了任务
ADAMA: You know the mission.
你们也该知道这次任务只能以一种方式结束
You should also know that there's only one way that this mission ends,
那就是从新卡布里卡成功营救我们的人民
and that's with the successful rescue of our people off of New Caprica.
祝作战成功
Good hunting.
Hoshi正在更新我们的地图坐标
Hoshi's working on updating our map coordinates
以便能搜索地球
for the search for Earth.
民用船只的船长想见你
DUALLA: Civilian captains want to meet with you.
他们有一堆问题  一堆麻烦
They have questions, problems.
和我说话  李
Talk to me, Lee.
我有点难以接受这个
I'm having trouble accepting this.
我知道  但我们必须坚持前进
I know. But we have to push forward,
保证舰队团结  找到地球
keep the Fleet together, find Earth.
没错  那是我们的责任
Right. That's our duty.
他们仍有机会回来的
There's still a chance they'll come back.
你父亲在他一生中创造了一个又一个奇迹
Your father has pulled off more than a few miracles in his day.
我也知道
I know that.
我也没有放弃希望
Yet I haven't given up hope.
不  你放弃了
Yes, you have.
我见到你从卡拉狄加回来后的表情
I saw the look on your face when you came back from Galactica.
就像要与他永别了似的
Like you were never gonna see him again.
我就这么容易被看透?
Am I that easy to read?
只有我才能看透你
Just to me.
对于一艘只有一半战斗力的太空堡垒来说  他要达到目的太难了
He's taking on too much for one half-strength battlestar to handle.
那不是个人看法  而是军事事实
That's not opinion. That's a military fact.
他这次再也回不来了 他们没有一个能回来了
He's not coming back from this. None of them are.
我们所能做的  就是为将来做打算
All we can do is make plans for the future.
我们得生存下来
We have to survive.
我们必须找到地球
We have to find Earth.
如果我们做不到  就不会再有人记得一个叫做威廉・阿达玛的人
If we don't, there'll be no one to remember a man named William Adama,
也不会记得一艘叫做卡拉狄加的太空堡垒
or a battlestar named Galactica.
这是我们肩负的责任
That is our charge to keep.
为了让人类能继续繁衍下去
To keep humanity going.
无论付出何种代价
No matter what the cost, no matter...
无论我们将要抛弃谁
No matter who we leave behind.
你能做到的  你能带领我们到达目的地
You can do this. You can get us there.
你是这个舰队的指挥官  你将带领我们到达安全的地方
You are commander of this fleet and you will guide us to safety.
为达此目的  你将不惜任何代价
And you will do it, no matter the cost.
因为你也姓阿达玛
Because you're an Adama.
我曾向你说过"我以与你共事为荣"吗?
Did I ever tell you how proud I am to serve with you?
没说过那么多字的
Not in so many words, no.
好吧  我以与你共事为荣  中尉
Well, I am proud to serve with you, Lieutenant.
也以你为我的妻子为荣
And to call you my wife.
现在我们讨论一下地图坐标  还有与那些船长们的会面
Now, let's talk about map coordinates, meeting with ships' captains...
今天我牺牲了三个人
I lost three men today,
而如果陆战队员没有出现的话 他们会把我们全部干掉的
and if that Marine sergeant wasn't on her game, they'd have killed us all.
我知道  见鬼  我知道了
I know, Gods damn it! I know!
你不用说个没完没了 我已经知道了  行不行?
You don't have to keep running your mouth about it. I get it, all right?
你明白了吗?  如果莎伦被杀
Do you get this? If Sharon had been killed,
我们不仅拿不到启动钥匙
not only would we not get the launch keys,
而且赛昂人将知道我们与卡拉狄加有直接联系
but the Cylons would know that we were in direct contact with Galactica.
那整个计划  整个城市的命运都将完蛋
Now, this whole plan... The fate of this whole city would have fallen apart.
你明白吗  上校?
Do you understand that, Colonel?
我明白
I get it.
好吧
Good. Hey,
你知道自己该做什么的
you know what has to be done here.
如果你不愿意做  我也理解
And if you don't want to do it, I understand.
但是相信我  上校  有些事情是必须要做的
But believe me, Colonel, someone is gonna do this.
为了她好  还是由你来做
Now, it would be better for her sake if it was you.
我不得不这么做  少  不得不
I had to do it, Saul. I had to.
我所做的一切都是为了你
It was all for you.
我想要你知道 为了救你 我愿意做任何事情
And I want you to know that I would've done anything to save you.
我明白  我明白  没关系  一切都会好起来的
I know. I know. It's all right. Everything's gonna be all right.
不  你不明白
No, you don't understand.
是我把你弄出监狱的  少  是我
I got you out of detention, Saul. It was me.
是我把你弄出来的
I got you out.
我去找他们 赛昂人
I went to see them. The Cylons.
最终找到了主管的那个人
Finally got to the one in charge.
然后  用男人注意我的方式  让他注意到我
And I got him to notice me the way men notice me.
我跟他上床了
I slept with him.
每当他用肮脏的手碰我的时候  我就想吐
I felt like puking every time he put his filthy hands on me.
但是我强颜欢笑  那是为了救你  少
But I smiled and I faked it to save you, Saul.
请听我说
But you listen to me.
我一次又一次与任何人上床  或是做任何事情
I'd do it again. Frak anybody, do anything,
甚至把地图交给他们
even give them the map.
我没想让任何人牺牲的
I didn't want anybody to be killed.
我可以喝那杯东西了
I could use a drink.
当我需要你的时候  你总在那儿等我
You've always been there for me when I need you.
噢  我感觉很累
I'm exhausted.
我感觉我只想这么靠在你身旁
I feel like I could just curl up here.
好吧
There. Attagirl.
我应该听你的话  少
I should've listened to you, Saul.
应该留在卡拉狄加上
Should've stayed on Galactica.
噢  现在什么也不用担心了
Oh, no, don't worry about any of that now.
你只...
You just...
好好去睡觉吧
You just go to sleep.
我睡了
So sleepy...
我爱你  你能听到我吗?
I love you, do you hear me?
我意思是  我告诉过你们  反复地说过
I mean, I've told you and I've told you,
但最终呢?
but to what end?
你们太自以为是  听不进意见
Too secure in your smug superiority to listen.
对你们成功的预期过于感觉良好
Too comfortable in your predictions of success
甚至丝毫不考虑失败的可能性
to even consider the possibility of defeat.
现在又怎样了呢?
And where are we now?
最重要的  劳拉・罗丝琳在哪?
And more to the point, where's Laura Roslin?
汤姆・查莱克在哪里?
Where's Tom Zarek?
大多数人呢?
At large.
那些未知派选民  选举里的自由派 或许与泰上校在一起
Whereabouts unknown, free at any rate. Probably with Colonel Tigh,
团结在叛军周围  用他们的幻想感召他们
solidifying the insurgency's hold over the public's imagination.
你到底想要我们怎样  盖尤斯?
What would you have us do, Gaius?
离开
Leave.
带上你们的赛昂武士  走吧
Pack up your Centurions and go.
请离开吧
Please go.
然后呢?
And then what?
如果我们真的把你留下  你会怎么做?
What would you do if we really just left you here?
平静地度过余生?
You'd live out your lives in peace
而永远不用再为与我们合作而烦恼了?
and never trouble yourselves with thoughts of us again?
或是你用赛昂人的故事来教育孩子们
Or would you raise your children with stories of the Cylon?
那些机器奴隶们起来反对你们
The mechanical slaves who once did your bidding only to turn against you.
那些对你们进行种族屠杀的凶手们
Killers who committed genocide against your race,
占领了城市  直到我们逃离
and the occupiers of this city until we just ran away.
你会让他们把这个故事讲给他们的孩子?
Would you tell them to tell the story to their children,
代代相传
and to their children's children,
并且保留一个复仇之梦 经过多年准备
and nurse a dream of vengeance down through the years,
直到有一天他们可以再次跨越星空
so that one day they could just go out into the stars
报复赛昂人
and hunt the Cylon once more?
血债血偿
Blood for blood.
终有一天会停止的
It has to stop one day.
喔  天呀
Oh, my Gods.
太近了    你在干嘛
MAN 1: That was pretty close. MAN 2: What are you doing?
快
WOMAN 1: Hurry!
干的漂亮  安德斯
Nice job, Anders.
来吧  来吧
Come on. Come on. Come on.
那是给我们的暗号  你们知道该怎么做
Okay, that's our cue. You know what to do.
集合你们的人  带他们到撤离点
Rally your people and get them to the evac points.
好了  按我们演练过的  你们能做好的
Okay, remember the drills, and you'll do fine.
神保佑你们  出发!出发!出发!
Go with the Gods. Go! Go! Go!
托瑞  你能告诉劳拉  我有多么感谢她吗?
Tory, would you tell Laura I cannot thank her enough...
等这一切结束后  你自己告诉她
Tell her yourself when this is all over.
希望我们都能像她这么镇静就好了   把他们都带到船上去 快
Wish we were all as calm as she is. Get them to their ship. Go!
是  女士        快去!
MAN 3: Yes, ma'am. Go!
是  女士
Yes, ma'am!
行动
MAN 4: Come on!
行动  行动
Let's move! Let's move!
好了  就是这些了  我们要攻击拘留中心
All right, this is it. We get to the detention center
而且会继续进攻 直到这里每一个人获得自由
and we do not stop until everybody is out of there, free.
每个人都知道各自的进入点 子弹上膛  我们现在出发
Everybody knows the rescue points, so let's load up and we move, right now!
我们出发  康纳
Let's move, Connor!
来吧  我们走
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
出发  出发
Move it! Head down!
佯攻中队正在接近发射点
Decoy squadron approaching launch point.
好了 就是这里了 伙计们  准备
KAT ON RADIO: Okay, this is it, guys. Stand by.
所有蝮蛇战机准备 就是现在!上!上!
All Vipers. Break now, now, now!
听我命令展开攻击 3...2...1...开火
Deploy drones on my mark. Three, two, one. Mark.
导弹信号匹配
KELLY: Drone signatures match.
赛昂人会在雷达上发现目标
Cylons should pick up the drones on dradis
会以为是两艘太空堡垒
and read them as two battlestars any minute.
转移所有囚犯…
Transport all the prisoners...
你被授命使用致命武器    什么?
D'ANNA: You're authorized to use deadly force. DORAL: What?
立即抽调V区的…
Immediate evac of sector V as in... V as in Victor.
我们可以派一些百夫长和武士…
SIMON: We could use some Centurions and warriors...
没有意义
For nothing.
全部没有意义
It's all for nothing.
我们可以重新来  盖尤斯  一座新的城市会在灰烬中重建
We'll start over, Gaius. A new city to rise out of the ashes.
它也将被埋葬
It'll be buried.
就像过去的那些城市一样
Buried like the cities of old.
被上帝的愤怒所毁灭
Consumed by the wrath of God.
两艘太空堡垒刚刚跳跃进入轨道
Two battlestars just jumped into orbit.
阿达玛回来了
Adama's back.
凯特  我是赛道  探测器显示有两艘基地之星
Kat, Racetrack. Two base ships on dradis,
方向002 定位015
bearing zero-zero-two carom zero-one-five.
他们发射了突袭机
They're launching Raiders.
红队 我是凯特
KAT ON RADIO: Red Squadron, Kat.
我们的任务完成了 全开引擎动力  我们离开这鬼地方
We've done our part. Kick in the turbos and let's get the hell out of here!
发生什么事?
STARBUCK: What's going on?
是叛乱份子 我会回来的
Insurgents. I'll be back.
你不能把我们关在这里
You cannot leave us trapped in here.
这里对你们最安全
It's the safest for you here.
不
STARBUCK: No!
上  我们上  快  快!
Let's go! Let's go!
汤姆  你们从那边走  去船坞
Tom, you go that way. Head to the shipyard.
你会来的  是吗?
You're coming, right?
我的船在那边
My ship's up there.
你这人还真有戏剧性   等下 劳拉
You sure have a sense for the dramatic. Hey, wait, Laura.
等一等 嘿 你是卡拉狄加上的 对吗?
Wait. Hey, you, you were on Galactica, right?
是的  我什么也没做      不  没事
Yeah. I didn't do anything! No, it's okay, it's okay.
你看着她  好吗?  别让她离开你的视线  走!
Keep an eye on her, all right? Don't let her out of your sight. Go!
上面见    上面见
See you up there. See you up there.
跳跃准备完成  绿色信号  准备完毕  长官
KELLY: Jump preparation complete. My board is green, ready to jump, sir.
蓝队准备就绪
Standby to launch Blue Squadron.
我是上将  全体注意  为震动做好准备
This is the Admiral. All hands, brace for turbulence.
基地之星刚刚接近堡垒目标了
D'ANNA: Base ships just closed on the battlestar targets.
没发现卡拉狄加  也没有发现帕伽索斯
There's no Galactica, no Pegasus.
导弹
Drones.
诱饵
Decoys.
整个事情是一个计谋
The whole thing's a trick.
卡拉狄加在哪里?
Where's Galactica?
高度99000  感觉象一块陨石
Altitude, 99,000, falling like a rock!
发射  全部发射!
Launch! Launch them all!
准备好超光速引擎
Standby, FTL!
准备发射
HELO ON RADIO: Clear for launch.
好吧  这应该是不同的
Well, this ought to be different.
他们准备完毕  准备
They're clear! Stand by.
跳跃
Jump.
蝮蛇战机  每个人都停火!
Vipers! Everybody, hold! Hold!
热狗  我是红翼
Hotdog, Redwing.
我看到友军在船坞大门外面受阻
There's two friendlies pinned down outside the shipyard gate!
收到  红翼  瞄准警卫塔
Roger, Redwing, target the guard tower.
我来控制大门  出击
I've got the gate. Pulling an odd!
来袭!
TYROL: Incoming!
我们走  快
That's it! Let's go! Let's go! Go! Go!
出发  出发
Let's go! Go! Move! Move!
起来
Get up!
前进  前进!我们出发!
Do it! Move! Move, move!
快走
Heads up!
Move! Let's move! Come on, move!
走 走    快  快
Move, move, move! MAN: Hurry up, hurry up!
准备起爆
Fire in the hole!
MATHIAS: Fire in the hole!
好了  我们出发!
All right, everybody, let's go.
这边
MAN: This way!
朝北部船场方向移动! 快!
Everyone to the shipyard! Move! Move! Hustle.
别停 快走
No stopping! Move!
门锁上了 下边有牢房
MAN:... locked doors! I see cells down there.
卡拉 听我说
Kara. Listen to me.
不
No. No.
我会把你带出去
I'll get you out of here.
所有部门报告损坏情况
All divisions make damage report to Combat.
主炮报告武器情况
Main batteries report weapon status.
雷达控制台?
Dradis?
重新开始工作
KELLY: Back online.
赛昂人基地之星从星云那边出现
Cylon base ships are coming out of the nebula.
正如我们所期望的 赛昂突袭机仍然没有发射
Just as we expected. Cylon Raiders are still scattered to hell and gone.
他们在没有战机掩护地情况下朝我们飞来
They're coming after us without fighter cover.
如果我们把这两艘基地之星从星球旁吸引过来
If we can draw the two base stars away from the planet,
地面上的人还有机会逃走
the colonists might be able to escape.
等一下 另外两艘基地之星跳进轨道
Hang on. Two more base ships just jumped into orbit.
现在我们必须对付四艘基地之星了  上将
We got four base ships out there, Admiral.
不 我们对付不了四艘
No. We can't hold off four.
把绳子给我
Pass up the cord!
顺便把另一边也绑起来
Hold still. Connect the other side right away.
我们丧失了机动能力了
We've lost maneuvering thrusters.
我们的左舷无法承受更多的攻击了
We can't take any more hits to port or we're looking
或者我们考虑将36区到48区进行爆炸泄压
at explosive decompressions in sections 36 through 48.
跳跃引擎呢?
Jump drives?
到此为止了
Then that's it.
这是一种荣誉
It's been an honor.
卡拉狄加  这是帕伽索斯  让我们来助你一臂之力吧
Galactica, Pegasus. Let us take some of this work off your hands.
准备好你们的超光速引擎 其余的就交给我们吧
APOLLO:Get your FTL up and ready and we'll take care of the rest.
准备  主炮开火
All right, fire up that main battery!
收到 长官
MAN: Roger that, sir!
见鬼  李
Damn you, Lee.
继续修复超光速引擎 让他们恢复上线
Keep working on those FTLs! Get 'em online!
是的  长官
Yes, sir!
赛昂人一旦恢复将重新部署
The Cylons will redeploy as soon as they recover.
谢谢你  李
Thank you, Lee.
他们来了 正在包围我们
DUALLA: They're coming about. Maneuvering to bracket us.
稳定航向 穿插到中间去
Steady as she goes. Take us right into the center.
我们那样坚持不了多久的
We won't last long in there.
不
No.
放我下来  放我下来
STARBUCK: Put me down! Put me down!
等等 停下! 放我下来!
Wait! Wait! Stop, stop! Put me down! Put me down!
哇  哇  卡拉  卡拉
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Kara, Kara!
真的是你吗?      宝贝  这真的是我
Is it really you? Yeah. Baby, it's really me,
听我说  我们没有时间了
but listen, we don't have time.
我们现在必须回到船上去 然后离开这该死的鬼星球
We're going to the ships, and we're gonna get the hell off this frakking planet.
好的  凯西在哪
Okay. Where's Kacey?
凯西是谁
Who's Kacey?
凯西  她是我女儿
Kacey. She's my daughter.
卡拉  凯西是谁?
Kara, who's Kacey?
她是我女儿!        卡拉  不  别
She's my daughter! Stop, we gotta... Kara, no!
我不能…
I can't...
该死  卡拉  回来!
Kara! Kara! Gods damn it, Kara, no!
让开 该死  卡拉! 回来
Out of the way! Come on! Gods damn it, Kara, no!
我们已经失去了地面控制权
We've lost control of the situation on the surface.
我们随时可以坐重型突袭机撤离
There's a Heavy Raider standing by, ready to evacuate us.
我们同意 全部撤离
We're agreed. Evacuate the entire facility.
我留下来引爆核弹
I'll stay behind and set off the nuke.
你也应该走  卡布里卡  还有你
You should go as well, Caprica. And you.
我想我们走了以后  你也不会留在这儿吧
I don't think you'll want to be here after we've gone.
我们也给你留了个地方
There's a place for you, too.
给我?
For me?
你是对的  我们错了
Well, you were right and we were wrong.
你应该得到奖励
There should be some reward for that.
盖尤斯  我们一起走吧
Gaius, we should go.
我只是想坐在这里等死
I just want to sit here and die.
你如愿以偿了  盖尤斯
GAETA: You're gonna get your wish, Gaius.
平民飞船正在起飞
KELLY: The ships are getting off the ground.
跳跃离开  只剩几艘了
Jumping away. Only a few left now.
超光速引擎恢复
FTL's back online!
帕伽索斯正遭到连续猛击  长官
Pegasus is taking a hell of a pounding, sir.
它周围好像连一架战机都没有
I don't think she has a single plane in the air.
李把所有战机都派去保护平民飞船了
Lee left all of his planes to guard the civilian ships.
他知道这次买的是单程票  他最终能脱险的
He knew this was a one-way trip. He'll evac before the end.
你确定?    让战机回航!
HELO: You sure? Land our birds!
我们离开这个鬼地方
Let's get the hell out of here!
全体战机 这是卡拉狄加 立即回航
HELO:All wings, Galactica. Come on home.
允许战斗紧急着陆 重复 立即回航
Combat landings authorized. Repeat, come on home!
全体人员 准备跳跃
All hands, all hands! Get ready to jump!
我相信过你
I believed in you.
等等  等等  盖塔
Whoa, whoa, Gaeta.
我相信过那个新卡布里卡的梦
I believed in the dream of New Caprica.
盖塔  我们同样相信过
Gaeta, we all did.
不是!  他没有
No! No. Not him.
他只相信盖尤斯・波塔尔的梦
He believed in the dream of Gaius Baltar.
安逸的生活 喝酒  磕药  不停地抓人
The good life. Booze, pills, hot and cold running interns.
他把我们引向灭亡
He led us to the apocalypse
但是我我...只是个...
and I... I turned out to be...
理想主义者
BALTAR: An idealist.
那没有罪
There's no sin in that.
你所描述我的每句话都是事实 每一个字
Everything you say about me is true. Every word.
但你要听我说
But you have to listen to me.
赛昂在这里准备了一枚核弹
The Cylons have a nuke in this complex.
没有任何人能活着离开这颗星球 除非我来阻止它爆炸
Nobody, and I mean nobody, is getting off this planet alive unless I stop D'Anna.
盖尤斯  她会杀了你
Gaius, she'll kill you.
就让她来杀我吧
Then she'll kill me.
要不就让盖塔先生来杀
Or it can be down to Mr. Gaeta.
不管谁杀  人类都会和我一起灭亡
Either way, the human race dies with me.
盖尤斯
CAPRICA SIX:Gaius.
继续  开枪吧
Go ahead, shoot.
你还等什么?
What are you waiting for?
请吧
Please. Please.
我求你了...
I'm begging you, please.
你还有机会改变这一切
You have one chance to put things right.
你明白我意思了吗?
Do you understand me?
快他妈的从这里滚出去  阻止核弹爆炸!快去!
Get the frak out of here! Stop that nuke! Go!
盖尤斯  我们走!
Gaius, let's go!
设定主炮按B模式自动循环射击  将引擎定为超速运转
APOLLO: Set main batteries to auto-fire, cycle B. Lock engines ahead flank.
我是指挥官  弃船  弃船
This is the Commander. Abandon ship, abandon ship.
全体人员弃船
All hands, abandon ship.
到猛禽机处报导  跳跃至会合点
Report to evac Raptors and jump to rendezvous point.
干得漂亮  到那里见
Good work, and I'll see you on the other side.
好了  快走  撤离! 我们走!
All right, people, let's move. Out! Let's go!
指挥官  你也快走
You, too, Commander.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
凯西!  凯西!
Kacey! Kacey!
凯西!宝贝你在哪儿?
Kacey, honey, where are you?
我就知道你会回来 我已经预见到了
I knew you'd be back. I saw it.
把凯西给我
Come here, Kacey.
说那句话
Say the words.
把她给我    说
Let me take her. Say them.
说什么?
What words?
你知道我想听的那个!
You know what I want.
我想听你亲口对我说出来  而且就像我对你说的那样
I want to hear you say them. And I want the rest of it. Just like I told you.
好吧 你赢了
Fine. You win.
我爱你
I love you.
再说一遍
Say it again.
我爱你
I love you.
那其他的呢?
Now the rest.
这就是你想得到的?
Was it everything you thought it would be?
我永远不会忘记这一刻
That and more. I'll never forget this moment.
我也不会
Neither will I.
以后再解释吧  我们走
I'll explain later. Let's move.
你确定她在里面?
BALTAR: Are you sure she's in there?
肯定在  我看着她进去的
Positive. I saw her go in.
他妈的骗子
Frakking liar.
是她  盖尤斯
It's her, Gaius.
上帝的第一个新子民
The first of God's new generation.
赫拉
Hera.
真是个奇迹
It's a miracle.
是上帝让她活了下来
Gods spared her.
赫拉
Hera.
我能抱抱吗?
Can I hold her?
不行!
CAPRICA SIX: No.
她不会引爆核弹了  再也不会了
She won't set off the nuke. Not anymore.
走吧  盖尤斯  我们该走了
Come on, Gaius, we have to go.
快走   好
Let's go. Go. Okay.
都登舰了
MAN 1: All aboard.
检查前面
MAN 2: Check up front.
我准备好走了
All right. I'm ready to go.
各位  这边走
All right, people, let's go, this way.
请在右舷机库暂时等候 直到我们把你们送去你们的新船上
Stand on the starboard hangar deck till we can get you to new ships.
大家请往这边走
Come on, people, all the way down.
这边  请往这边走  走吧
All the way down, people, all the way down. Let's go!
噢  天呀
Oh, my Gods.
上尉吗?  我还以为你死了呢
Captain? I thought you were dead.
是呀  我也是
Yeah, so did I.
嘿  这是谁?
Anyway, well, who's this?
没错  我也正想问她
Yeah, I was gonna ask that myself.
这是…
STARBUCK: This is...
凯西?
Kacey?
凯西  噢  我的乖女儿
Kacey! My little girl!
妈妈可想死你了
Mommy missed you so much.
谢谢你 谢谢
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
当赛昂人带走她的时候  我以为...
When the Cylons took her I... I thought...
但你把她救了
But you saved her.
神保佑你
Gods bless you.
嗨
Hey.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
欢迎登舰 欢迎
Welcome aboard. Welcome.
欢迎登舰
Welcome aboard.
我猜你没看懂我的命令
I guess you didn't understand my orders.
从来就没看懂过你写的字
Never could read your handwriting.
请求准许登舰  长官
TIGH: Permission to come aboard, sir?
嗨
Hey.
准许登舰
Permission granted.
你做到了 你把他们都带回来了 少
You did it. You brought 'em home, Saul.
但不是所有人
Not all of them.
对不起
I'm sorry.
阿达玛!阿达玛!
ALL:Adama! Adama! Adama! Adama!
Adama! Adama! Adama! Adama!
我们仔细检查过了舰队的人员名单
We're still double-checking the Fleet's manifests,
但是玛雅似乎没能逃出新卡布里卡
but it doesn't look like Maya made it off of New Caprica.
婴儿怎么样?
What about the baby?
当时我让两个士兵负责把他们带上船
I was there when the two guards left to take them to their ship.
后来怎样我就不知道了
I don't know what happened.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我知道我让你失望了
I let you down and I know that.
不  你没有让我失望
No, you didn't.
这不是你的过错
It's not your fault.
这不是我们所能控制的
This is bigger than us.
这就是命运
This is life.
所有飞行员去14号通道报道
MAN ON PA: All pilots proceed to gate 14.
准备接受任务分配
Stand by for ship assignments.
所有飞行员去14号通道报道 准备接受任务分配
All pilots proceed to gate 14. Stand by for ship assignments.